# Shubhangi Agarwal

🕋 shubhangiat.github.io | 🛅 shubhangi-agarwal

■ shubhangi.agarwal8@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

I am a researcher with a background in Graph Mining and Machine Learning. I have developed various algorithms based on statistical analysis for Subgraph Querying in large complex graphs. Some of the many areas that can benefit from the querying of subgraph structures are information extraction, recommendation systems, disease diagnostics, fraud detection are. I am intersted in developing effective and efficient algorithms for analyzing complex data structures using state-of-the-art machine learning techniques.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh, India

**Bachelor of Technology Computer Engineering** 

Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology, Surat, Gujarat, India

CGPA: 8.25 2014 - current

Supervisor: Arnab Bhattacharva

CGPA: 8.71 2010 - 2014

# **PHD THESIS**

## **Subgraph Matching and Mining in Large Graphs**

Developed algorithms for Approximate Subgraph Matching in both deterministic and probabilistic graphs.

Proposed a Graph Neural Network model for robust node embeddings with positional information.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- "VeNoM: Approximate Subgraph Matching with Enhanced Neighbourhood Structural Information", Shubhangi Agarwal, Sourav Dutta and Arnab Bhattacharya, 7th Joint International Conference on Data Science and Management of Data (CODS-COMAD), 2024, India.
- "VerSaChI: Finding Statistically Significant Subgraph Matches using Chebyshev's Inequality", Shubhangi Agarwal, Sourav Dutta and Arnab Bhattacharya, Proceedings of the International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), 2021, pages 2812-2816, Australia.
- "GraphReach: Position-Aware Graph Neural Network using Reachability Estimations", Sunil Nishad, Shubhangi Agarwal, Arnab Bhattacharya and Sayan Ranu, Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2021, pages 1527-1533, Canada.
- "ChiSeL: Graph Similarity Search using Chi-Squared Statistics in Large Probabilistic Graphs", Shubhangi Agarwal, Sourav Dutta and Arnab Bhattacharya, Proceedings of the International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB), 2020, pages 1654-1668, Japan.

#### **EXPERIENCES**

**External Reviewer** 2020 - current

WSDM (2024), CIKM (2021, 2022), DASFAA (2022), CoDS-COMAD (2020, 2021), KDD (2021)

# **Teaching Assistant (IIT Kanpur)**

Aug 2014 - Apr 2021

• Graded and evaluated projects for various courses of Computer Science.

# **Senior Tutor (IIT Kanpur)**

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018, Aug 2019 - Apr 2020

• Led teams of strength  $\sim$ 60; Assisted in backend management, paper-setting and grading.

#### **Teaching Assistant for MOOC (NPTEL - Remote)**

July 2017 - Sep 2017

• Crafted objective questions and resolved student queries on Fundamentals of Database Systems.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

: C, C++, Java, Python, R, MySQL, JavaScript, PHP, Shell scripting Languages

**Libraries** : PyTorch, Tensorflow, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas

**Tools** : git, LaTeX, Docker, Weka **J** +91 81728 39867